Register of the Warren Christopher papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Warren Christopher papers
1927-2011
2014C29
Hoover Institution Archives
35 manuscript boxes, 12 oversize boxes (19.4 linear feet)
The Warren Christopher papers document the career of an American statesman who held government posts under three presidents, most notably serving as secretary of state during the first term of Bill Clinton's administration (1993-1997). The largest part of the collection relates to this period and mainly concerns the public side of Christopher's time as head of the State Department. In particular, there are press releases, speeches, and photographs relating to official trips and meetings. There are also materials in the papers pertaining to Christopher's other government posts, as well as to his long career as a lawyer with a major firm in Los Angeles. The last part of the collection contains numerous video recordings of speeches by Christopher, as well as of his appearances before committees of the U.S. Congress.
Christopher, Warren.
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Biographical Chronology
1925 October 27 Born, Scranton, North Dakota
1943-1946 Served in U.S. Navy
1949 Awarded J.D. degree, Stanford Law School
1950-1967 Practiced law with firm of O'Melveny and Myers
1965 Member, Governor's Commission on the Los Angeles Riots
1967-1969 U.S. deputy attorney general
1974-1975 President, Los Angeles County Bar Association
1977-1981 U.S. deputy secretary of state
1991 Chairman, Independent Commission on the Los Angeles Police Department
1993-1997 U.S. secretary of state
1998 Author, In the Stream of History: Shaping Foreign Policy for a New Era
2001 Author, Chances of a Lifetime
2011 Died
Scope and Contents note
The Warren Christopher papers document the career of an American statesman who held government posts under three presidents, most notably serving as secretary of state during the first term of Bill Clinton's administration (1993-1997). The largest part of the collection relates to this period and mainly concerns the public side of Christopher's time as head of the State Department. In particular, there are press releases, speeches, and photographs relating to official trips and meetings. There are also materials in the papers pertaining to Christopher's other government posts, as well as to his long career as a lawyer with a major firm in Los Angeles. The last part of the collection contains numerous video recordings of speeches by Christopher, as well as of his appearances before committees of the U.S. Congress.
As secretary of state, Christopher was directly involved in the negotiations that led to the 1995 Dayton Agreement that ended the civil war in Bosnia. He also facilitated the signing of the 1993 Oslo Accords between Israel and the Palestine Liberation Organization that resulted in the establishment of the Palestinian Authority. While the Christopher papers do not reveal the inner workings of these diplomatic undertakings, they do contain information on the general lines of American diplomacy during Christopher's term in office.
Christopher had previously served as deputy secretary of state during the Carter administration, and he played a major role in efforts to resolve the Iranian hostage crisis, helping to secure the release of those Americans held captive in Iran. He also led the Carter administration's successful efforts to have the Panama Canal treaties ratified by the U.S. Senate.
Prior to this, Christopher had been appointed deputy attorney general by Lyndon Johnson. In this position, he led the government response to the Detroit riots in 1967. He already served on an official commission that investigated the 1965 Watts riots in Los Angeles. Later he was chairman of a commission set up in response to the 1991 Los Angeles riots.
Christopher was an important figure on the national level in the Democratic Party. He headed the search that led to Bill Clinton's selection of Al Gore as his vice presidential running mate in 1992; he also headed the presidential transition team for Clinton after his election victory. In the controversy surrounding the outcome of the 2000 presidential election, Christopher served as Al Gore's representative during the recount of the vote in Florida.
Significant parts of the collection detail these other aspects of Christopher's public career. These materials consist largely of correspondence, reports, press releases, and photographs.
United States. Department of Justice.; United States. Department of State.; Statesmen--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--1977-1981.; United States--Foreign relations--1993-2001.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; Video tapes.
- Speech on the United Nations by Cyrus Vance, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Photographs of visit to Elmendorf Air Force Base, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Report on the United Nations and identification badge, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Photographs of Marie Christopher's visit to Jakarta, Indonesia, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Articles about Warren Christopher, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Celebration book presented to Raymond Seitz, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Report on accomplishments of Clinton administration, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Remarks by Bill Clinton on Warren Christopher, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 8-9)
- Miscellaneous thank you notes, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Photographs, 1996-1997
  - With Jiang Zemin, 1997 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - With Bill Clinton, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Letter from Bill Clinton accepting Warren Christopher's resignation as Secretary of State, 1996 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- Clippings relating to Bill Clinton, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Report on foreign policy record of Clinton administration, 2001 (Box-folder 1: 15)
- Miscellaneous invitations, 1995-1997
  - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1995-1997 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1994-1996
  - 1994 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1995 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
- Photographs, 1992-1998
  - State Department, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Clinton administration, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 3: 3-5)
  - Post-Clinton administration, 1998 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Postcard, 1994 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Clippings, 1996 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Photographs, 1992-1996
  - Africa, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Argentina, 1996 (Box-folder 4: 3-4)
  - Brussels, Belgium, 1994 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Cambodia, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - China, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Dayton, Ohio negotiations on Bosnia, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Japan, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Kuwait, 1993 (Box-folder 4 :10)
  - Miscellaneous Europe, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Paris, France, 1994 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - South Korea, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Spain, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Stuttgart, Germany, 1996 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Vietnam, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Haiti, 1994 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Helsinki, Finland, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Israel, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 3-8)
  - Jordan, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Miscellaneous Middle East, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Moscow, Russia, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Mexico City, Mexico, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
  - Santiago, Chile, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - São Paulo, Brazil, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 4-8)
- Speeches, 1992
  - By Bill Clinton, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - By Warren Christopher, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
- Vice Presidential Selection Project, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 5-7)
- Clinton Transition Team, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 8-9)
- Clinton dinner, 1992
  - Photographs (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Notes for speech, 1992 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Statements relating to appointment as Secretary of State, 1992 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Press conference in 1992 relating to selection of Al Gore as vice presidential candidate, 1988-1992
  - Recording on compact sound cassette, 1992 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Background report, 1988 (Box-folder 8: 5)
- Government questionnaires, 1992 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Confirmation hearings on nomination as Secretary of State, 1993
  - Statement, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Transcripts, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 8-9)
- Miscellaneous speeches and statements, 1993-1997
  - Indexes, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - 1993 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - 1995 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - 1997 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- Honorary degrees, 1981-2007
  - Diploma from California State University, Los Angeles, 2007 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Letter from Ferdinand F. Fernandez, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Photographs, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 6)
- Miscellaneous photographs, 1993 (Box-folder 9: 7)
- Clippings about Warren Christopher, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 9: 8-9)
- Interviews, 1995-1996
  - 1995
    - January (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - February (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - March (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - April (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - May-June (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - July (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - September-October (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - November-December (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - 1996
    - January-March (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - April-May (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - May-July (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - August-December (Box-folder 11: 3)
- Calendars, 1993-1997
  - 1993 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - 1993-1994 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - 1993-1997 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - 1995 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - 1995-1997 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- International travel chronology, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- Daily schedules, 1993-1997
  - 1993
    - January-May (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - June-December (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - 1994
    - January-May (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - June-December (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - 1995
    - January-May (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - June-December (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - 1996
    - January-May (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - June-December (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - 1997 January (Box-folder 13: 4)
- Printed matter relating to Warren Christopher, 1982-2012
  - 1982-1989 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - 1998-2001 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - 2003-2006 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - 2010-2011 (Box-folder 14: 2)
- Oral history interviews, 1997-2002
  - Briefing materials, 2002 (Box-folder 14: 4-5)
  - Transcripts, 1997-2002 (Box-folder 14: 6-7)
- Editorial analysis index, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Major addresses, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Ministerial interventions, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Remarks at historic ceremonies, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 15: 4)
- Congressional testimony, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- Op-ed pieces, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 15: 6)
- Compilation of quotes, 1993-2006 (Box-folder 15: 7)
- Doyle McManus file, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 15: 8)
- Congressional resolution, 1997 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Remarks at dinner for Bill Clinton, 1992 (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Remarks by Bill Clinton on Warren Christopher's leaving office of Secretary of State, 1996 (Box-folder 16: 3)
- Cartoons and jokes, 1996 (Box-folder 16: 4)
- Clippings about Warren Christopher, 1967-1998
  - Clinton campaign and transition, 1992 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Clinton administration, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - General, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 16: 7)
- Newspaper summaries, 1993 (Box-folder 16: 8)
- Briefing memos, 1993-1994
  - 1993 (Box-folder 16: 9-10)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 16: 11)
- Correspondence, 1969-2011
  - Bush, Geoge W., 2006 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalyn, 1978-2009 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Johnson, Lyndon and Lady Bird, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Lieberman, Joe, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Obama, Barack (letter of condolence to Marie Christopher), 2011 (Box-folder 16: 15)
- Photographs, 1967-2000
  - Clinton administration, 1993-1997
    - General, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - Camp David album, 1993 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - From Bill Clinton, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - White House album, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - With Al Gore, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - From Jimmy Carter, 1979 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - With Kofi Annan, 1998 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-2000 (Box-folder 17: 9-10)
- Correspondence, 1970-2010
  - Clinton, Bill, 1997-2010 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Clinton, Hillary, 1993-2010 (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - Gore, Al, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Mondale, Walter, 1984-1996 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-2008 (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Farewell messages, 1996-1997
    - Cabinet and ambassadors, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 17: 16)
    - Congress, 1997 (Box-folder 17: 17)
    - Senate, 1997 (Box-folder 17: 18)
    - Foreign dignitaries, 1997 (Box-folder 17: 19)
- Personal correspondence, 1993-1996
  - 1993
    - January (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - February (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - March (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - April (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - June (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - July-September (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - October-December (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - 1994
    - January (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - February (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - March (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - April-May (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - June (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - July-August (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - September (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - October (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - November (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - December (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - 1995
    - January-February (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - March (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - April (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - May-June (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - July-August (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - September (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - November-December (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - 1996
    - January (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - February-March (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - April (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - May (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - July (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - August-September (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - October (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - November-December (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - 1997
    - January (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
  - Letters from friends and colleagues, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 23: 6-7)
- Interview transcripts, 1997 January (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Iran hostage crisis materials, 1979-2004
  - Photographs of agreement signing, 1981 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Remarks at prayer breakfast, 1981 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Book chapter, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Remarks on 25th anniversary, 2004 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Historical overview, 1992 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Clippings, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 24: 7-8)
  - Clippings, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Serial issues, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 2-3)
- Carter administration materials, 1976-1994
  - Miscellany, 1981-1994 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Panama Canal treaties, 1978-1993 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Speeches, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Photographs, 1977-1981
    - Deputy Secretary of State swearing in ceremony, 1977 (Box-folder 25: 8)
    - NATO press conference, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 9)
    - State Department, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
    - Taiwan, 1978 (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 26: 4-5)
  - Speeches, 1977-1980
    - 1977 (Box-folder 26: 6)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 26: 8)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Scrapbook, 1965-1981 (Box-folder 27: 2-6)
- Johnson administration materials, 1967-1969
  - Photographs, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Report on Detroit riots, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Oral history, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Letter from Harold Johnson, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - List of contacts with Lyndon Johnson, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Speech by John Brademas, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967
    - Christopher, Catherine Anne, 1967 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Johnson, Lyndon, 1967 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    - Copies of documents from Johnson Library, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 28: 3-4)
- Clippings, 1965-1994
  - 1965-1979 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - 1967 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 28: 7-8)
  - 1981-1994 (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Scrapbook, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 29: 2-3)
- Speeches, 1981-2010
  - 1981 (Box-folder 29: 4-6)
  - 1982 (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 30: 4-5)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - 1985 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - 1990 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - 1991 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - 1992 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - 1997 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - 1998 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - 1998 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - 1999-2000 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - 2002-2003 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - 2004-2010 (Box-folder 32: 5)
- Los Angeles riots materials, 1990-1992
  - Inventory of documents (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Statements by Warren Christopher, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Photographs, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Summary of report, 1991 (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Op-ed pieces, 1997-2010 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Watts riots materials, 1965-1966
  - Clippings and photographs, 1965 (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Report, 1965 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - Speech, 1966 (Box-folder 33: 4)
- Notes for Elliot Richardson on possible appointment as Watergate prosecutor, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 5)
- Correspondence, 1961-1973
  - Brown, Edmund G., 1961-1973 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Brown, Jerry, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1961 (Box-folder 33: 8)
- Biographical materials, 1960-2010
  - Announcements of awards and achievements, 1974-2006 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1960-2010 (Box-folder 33: 10)
- Copies of documents from Johnson and Carter Libraries, 1945-1967 (Box-folder 33: 11)
- Photographs, 1927-2010
  - Portraits, 1950-2010 (Box-folder 33: 12)
  - Childhood and student years, 1927-1948 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Service in U.S. Navy, 1945 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - In Los Angeles, 1958-1988 (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - With Tom Bradley, 1979 (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - With Pervez Musharraf, 2003 (Box-folder 33: 17)
- William O. Douglas file, 1948-2003 (Box-folder 33: 18)
- Background materials for speeches, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 34: 1-3)
- Al Gore presidential campaign file, 1997-2003
  - Vice-presidential nominee search, 2000 (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Bush v. Gore article and speech, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 34: 6)
- Biographical timelines, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 34: 7)
- National War Powers Commission report, 2009 (Box-folder 34: 8)
- Warren Christopher memorial file, 2010
  - Program for memorial gathering, 2010 (Box-folder 34: 9)
  - DVD videorecording of memorial gathering, 2010 (Box-folder 34: 10)
  - State Department compilation of condolences, 2010 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  - Compilation of testaments and clippings, 2011 (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Printed matter, 1991-2013
  - Collected speeches, 2005
    - Diplomacy: The Neglected Imperative, 2005 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - Random Harvest (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Pamphlets relating to the Warren Christopher Scholarship Awards, 2011-2013 (Box-folder 35: 4-5)
  - Reports, 1991-2000
    - Governor's Advisory Panel on Hate Groups, 2000 (Box-folder 35: 6)
    - Independent Commission on the Los Angeles Police Department, 1991 (Box-folder 35: 7)
- Oversize materials
  - Photo albums, 1976-1996
    - Trip to Oslo, Norway, 1994 (Box-folder 36: 1-3)
    - Trip to Vietnam, 1995 (Box-folder 36: 4)
    - Visit to USS George Washington, 1994 (Box-folder 36: 5)
    - Trip to Mali, 1996 (Box-folder 36: 6-10)
    - Trip to Australia, 1996 (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - Trip to China and reception for Jiang Zemin, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 37: 2)
    - Swearing in ceremony for Clinton cabinet, 1993 (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - Trip to Brazil, 1977 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Scrapbook of years in Carter administration, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 38: 2)
  - Photographs, 1977-1995
    - Carter administration portfolio, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - With Yitzhak Rabin, 1994 (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - With Al Gore, 1995 (Box-folder 39: 3-4)
  - Photo album relating to being awarded honorary doctorate by California State University, Los Angeles, 2007 (Album 39: 5)
  - Awards and commendations, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 39: 6-16)
  - Plaque from Independent Commission on the Los Angeles Police Department, 1991 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Photographs, 1978-2000
    - Framed photograph with Shimon Peres and others, 2000 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Official portraits, 1993 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - With Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Close up of signing of Iran hostage agreement, 1981 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - With Arthur Goldberg, 1979 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Group portrait of Clinton administration, 1993 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - With William Perry and John M. Shalikashvili, 1996 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - At gravesite of Yitzhak Rabin, 1996 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    - Jimmy Carter, George Bush, Bill Clinton, and Gerald Ford, 2000 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Bill and Hillary Clinton, 1993 (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - Metal reproduction of front page of New York Times with article on Dayton agreement on Bosnia, 1995 (Box-folder 40: 12)
  - Signed reproduction of political cartoon, 1978 (Box-folder 40: 13)
- Videorecordings, 1992-2008
  - Betacam SP videocassette recording of press conference at Indiana University, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - DVD disc containing "The 16th Report of the Secretaries of State", 2008 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - VHS videocassettes, 1992-2006
    - "A Force More Powerful: A Century of Nonviolent Conflict", 2000 (Box-folder 41: 3-4)
    - "Ambassador Under Fire Overseas", 2002 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - "People Achieving Their Dreams," Achievable Foundation, 1998 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - "1st Annual Political Roast: John Ferraro," American Diabetes Association, 1998 (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - "APEC EduNet Presentation," University of Washington, 1996 (Box-folder 41: 8)
    - BBC interview with David Frost, 1996 (Box-folder 41: 9)
    - Worldnet program on Bosnia, 1993 (Box-folder 41: 10)
    - "Bringing Down a Dictator: The Defeat of Slobodan Milosevic", 2001 (Box-folder 41: 11)
    - "6th Annual Abe Lincoln Remembrance," Los Angeles, 1998 (Box-folder 41: 12)
    - PBS interview with Charlie Rose, 2001 (Box-folder 41: 13-14)
    - Speech to State Department employees, 1993 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - ABC Good Morning America program appearance, 2001 (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - Tokyo trip, 1993 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Fulfillment Fund speech, 1996 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - Farewell remarks as Secretary of State, 1997 (Box-folder 42: 5-6)
    - Face the Nation program appearance and testimony given to Senate Appropriations Committee, 1993 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    - Al Gore speech at Democratic National Convention, 2000 (Box-folder 42: 8)
    - Dean Acheson stamp dedication address, 1993 (Box-folder 42: 9)
    - Media appearances, 1993 (Box-folder 42: 10-12)
    - CNN interview, 1996 (Box-folder 42: 13)
    - Global Event, 1996 (Box-folder 42: 14)
    - PBS Newshour interview with Jim Lehrer, 1994 (Box-folder 42: 15)
    - Testimony before House Foreign Affairs Committee, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 43: 1-8)
    - Testimony before House Appropriations Commitee, 1993 (Box-folder 43: 9-11)
    - "Global Review 2000 with World Leaders" (Box-folder 43: 12)